

Senior Software Engineer

cs.aymanmubark@gmail.com

+966558413580

🤈 Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Sudanese, Male, Single.

✓ Transferable Igama

aymanmubark.github.io

Experienced Software Engineer with 5+ years in industry and high-level proficiency in the following: Dart, Agile, REST API, SQL, Firebase, Google Maps, MS Server, Git, .Net Core, TFS, VB.net, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript I am on Great knowledge and experience in planning, building, and testing software projects with my experience in developing mobile and web applications. Multicultural work experience, highly motivated and committed to providing professional solutions in a timely and efficient manner.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer

Nittag for Information Technology - Riyadh | 2021 - 2022

Worked as a Software Engineer in Nittaq for Information Technology. Nittaq for Information Technology is a pioneer and specialized in the world of IT solutions and advanced innovative solutions. developed flutter mobile apps with following: Firebase, Github, Web API, Google Map Google Maps Platform, Online Payment, Clean Code, State Management ...

Software Engineer

Blueprint Technology - Khartoum | 2020 - 2021

Worked as a software engineer in Blueprint Technology in several web and mobile applications in many business fields like e commerce ERP and design structure for project like e bay with the following: C#, Agile, ASP.Net MVC, .Net Core, Signalr, EF, Migration, SQL Server, Firebase, MVC, IIS, Nginx, Blazor OOD, SOLID, Flutter, Google Map, Online Payment ...

Backend Developer

Al-Takamul Al-Tegani - Sharjah | 2019 - 2020

Worked as a Backend Developer at Al-Takamul Al-Teqani Computers in the United Arab Emirates. I help to develop numbers of successful projects that worked in many The Arab Gulf States, that produces smart technological solutions with following C#, Agile, ASP.Net, .Net Core, Signalr, EF, Migration, SQL Server, Firebase, MVC, IIS, Nginx, OOD, SOLID...

Software Engineer

Optima - Khartoum | 2017 - 2019

Worked as a software engineer in Optima for Software Solutions here in Sudan, I participated in one of Sudan's E-government large-scale projects, an ERP system to the Ministry of Investment (Gezira state) and I develop several desktop applications with many Microsoft technologies (C#, VB.Net, ASP.NET, EF, MS SQL ...

EDUCATION

B.A. Honors of Computer Science at University of Gezira (2014 - 2020)

PROJECTS

EPT

UK

EBT is the World's 1st Al-driven football training app that gives you attribute-specific drills and position-specific sessions. Not only that but stay motivated and improve your game with our innovative scoring system that allows you to track your performance with features such as instant Al feedback, progression tracking, and drill scheduler. I responsible to add futures like social media login (Apple, Google, Facebook). Website

Ameera

Sudan

A Ameera is a comprehensive App providing all beauty and health services from the best artists in Sudan at customers' homes. These services include beauty and health services such as Henna and hair care in addition to products such as accessories, cosmetics, and more. I developed two mobile applications for customers and service providers using flutter. I was also responsible to build many futures like google Maps and order trucking and the admin dashboard. Provider App, Customer App

Shifaty

Saudi Arabia

Shifaty application is a link between chefs and customers through chatting with the ability to order food and pay online with price comparison between more than one chef, I developed a mobile application using flutter framework and redesigned the user interface for some screens How much I added the instant chat feature between customers and chef using Firebase I also used Google Maps and electronic payment. Website

Som

Saudi Arabia

The Som Haraj application displays all local goods and products from real estate, vehicles, devices, services, etc., and your requests can be placed to facilitate access to the owners as well, I developed a mobile application using flutter framework I added following features like push notifications and chatting between customers and Google deMaps. Apple

Butikati

Saudi Arabia

Butikati foundation for marketing services seeks to meet the needs of business owners to be pioneers in activating technology and investing it in the optimal investment to develop the value of their competitive stores and their market share, as we do this by providing a lot of diverse and integrated electronic and marketing services in One platform. I developed a mobile application for customers and service providers using flutter and, I added some features like social media login (Google, Apple, Facebook) ... Website

Monjid

Sudan

Monjid is an auto services platform that offers roadside assistance 24/7 and reaches customers in their places. Monjid offers roadside assistance services, including tire services, battery services, and towing services and Monjid offers oil change services. I developed two mobile applications for customers and service providers using flutter and suggested some UI/UX design changes. I was also responsible for backend coding (Asp.Net core, C#, EF, Web APIs) and the admin dashboard. Google Play

Blood Bank Sudan

Sudan

One of the problems of blood banks in Sudan is the lack of discrimination in state institutions and the weakness of their management. The number of cases in Sudan that need hundreds of bloods each year could have been saved. Sudan blood bank. Application whose main goal is to provide blood donors at any moment. I planned and made this project with flutter for mobile application and Asp.net core web API. Google Play

Qareeb

Sudan

Qareeb is a Sudanese application delivering anything you want to someone else or vice versa where the customer selects the place of receipt and delivery I build. I developed web API for customers and provider using ASP.net and SQL server and provider API documentation (swagger). I was also responsible for backend coding (Asp.Net core, C#, EF, Web APIs) and the admin dashboard with many futures.

I Student

United Arab Emirates

An intelligent system manufactured to meet the needs and safety of school students. The product is breaking the barrier of innovative technology. I Student is a system that unites students' needs, parents' concerns, and the efficiency of school management. I was responsible for building the API for the Parents App and the Bus Supervisor by using Asp.Net Web API and admin dashboard, and I learn how to build a real-time service for tracking buses using firebase real-time database ... About

Smart E-pay

United Arab Emirates

Smart E-Pay is a point-of-sale solution that comes in various forms of customized software implemented in POS machines, increasing the productivity and functionality of company and organization owners. Based on Smart E-Pay's customizable software. It inquires specific orders of selected services by the consumer, which follows the insisting of the order & the desired payment method I participated in the smart e-pay refactoring, and I was also responsible for backend coding (Asp.Net core, C#, EF, Web APIs)... About

Home Care

Sudan

Home Care e-shopping application, an application that allows its users to view and purchase Home Care products in an easy and distinct way. Features of the application: application Determine delivery locations Find out the prices of products using barcodes Browse and view photos and product information Pay using the electronic payment service. I participated in the Home Care refactoring, and I was also responsible for front coding (flutter). Google Play

Ministry of Investment and Industry Management System

Sudan

It is a system for the Sudanese government created to handle internal transactions in the Ministry of Investment and Industry, Gezira State, Sudan. The Ministry uses the system to register companies and generate commercial licenses for these companies. I built this system using (VB.NET, SQL Server, Crystal Reports, DevExpress).

SKILLS

Technical

Dart/Flutter Agile Firebase (Singin, FCM, RDB) C#

Asp.Net Core Unit Test Signalr Asp.Net MVC

Web APIDesign PatternEntity FrameworkSQL, SQL Server, MySQLOOD, SOLID, MVCDesign & implement databaseUnit TestsAzure, Cloud, IIS, Nginx

.NET Version Control (Git, TFS) HTML, CSS, jQuery Blazor

Professional

- Effective communication
- Team player
- Good time management

COURSES

Flutter UI Masterclass | iOS & Android in Dart

<u>Udemy</u> | 05/2020

Learn how to build beautiful and comprehensive iOS and Android user interfaces using Flutter and Dart. This course will teach you how to build the UI of three amazing mobile apps.

ASP NET Core Tutorial

Pragim Technologies | 04/2020

This free step by step asp.net core tutorial for beginners is a 20-hour course. We discussed all the asp.net core MVC concepts from basics to advance to help you build real-world web applications.

The Complete 2019 Flutter Development Bootcamp

<u>Udemy</u> | 11/2019

Officially created in collaboration with the Google Flutter team, build beautiful, fast and native-quality apps with Flutter Become a fully-fledged Flutter developer.

ASP.NET MVC 5 Project - CMS

Udemy | 01/2018

A practical course in ASP.NET MVC 5 This course covers a tone of techniques and will make you able to create your own custom websites with ASP.NET MVC and Entity Framework.

VB 2012

Wagf Online | 01/2016

The course of the Visual Basic 2012 for the trainer Ahmed Ziney, which explains: the principles of Visual Basic on the console and then dealing with forms and then link the Visual Bassat databases.

LANGUAGES INTERESTS AWARDS

- English (Work Range)
- Arabic (Native)
- Games
- Cooking

Best MVP Mix2Build (2019)

Behance

IEEE Member (2018)